Can Bogoclu, PhD

♥ Düsseldorf, Germany | ★ canbooo.github.io

□ can.bogoclu@gmail.com | □ canbooo | R⁶ Can-Bogoclu | □ can-bogoclu

personal summary

Lang.: Turkish, 7+ years of experience in machine learning • small data and active learning expertise English, German

• experience with big data and distributed training • highly skilled at visualization • endless love for learning and teaching • secret crush on reinforcement learning

Nation.: Turkish

Legal: EU Blue Card for Germany

experience

Applied Scientist

Zalando SE since July 2022

Probabilistic fulfillment and delivery time estimation

- Significant accuracy and precision improvement already in the second month
- Distributed training on AWS using workflows and step functions
- Agile team and methodology

Probabilistic and deep learning

learning

Bayesian

machine learning

optimization Uncertainty

quantification

Hypothesis testing

Python | 8+ yrs

bash | 6+ yrs

git | 4+ yrs

Reinforcement Associate Lecturer

Niederrhein University of Applied Sciences

Oct. 2019-Sep. 2022

- Math for first year engineering students (1 semester)
- Computer science for engineering students (2 semesters)
- Introduction to Machine Learning for computer science students (1 semester)
- Probabilistic machine learning for engineering students (1 semester)
- Mentored a PhD student

development (Senior) Software Developer and Data Scientist

Probaligence GmbH

Sep. 2018-June 2022

- STOCHOS, an automated machine learning module for engineers. Flavors: python module, web-based GUI, ANSYS optiSlang add-in.
- KILu, AI research for aviation, partner: German Aerospace Center (DLR). Topics: material modelling, geometric mesh analysis
- RLTC, RL for trajectory control, partner: ZF Friedrichshafen AG. Task: Uncertainty aware reinforcement learning for autonomous vehicles
- iFoot, intelligent bandage for diabetic foot. Tasks: Smart watch app, Web servers for data pipeline and patient tracking

tools

tensorflow, torch jax, scikit-learn xaboost

Javascript | 1+ yrs

pandas, dask matplotlib, dash seaborn, plotly

django, selenium

ray, dvc

pytest, nose unittest

databases

Research Assistant

Niederrhein University of Applied Science

Jan. 2015-Oct. 2019

2015-2022

- MeZuMe, electric motor uncertainty optimization, partner: Bosch GmbH
- Learning from vector and field data for structural anomaly detection
- High-performance computing cluster administration

AWS Lambda/Step docker

education

PhD Mechanical Engineering, Ruhr-Universität Bochum

Thesis: Machine learning accelerated design uncertainty optimization

Diplom (B.Sc. + M.Sc.) Mechanical Engineering, RWTH Aachen Thesis: Modelling and experimental validation of hydraulic pump housings

SQLite | 2+ yrs postgresql | 1+ yrs